



Poltoratsky Max

Male, 37 years, born on 2 December 1985

+7 (960) 6288683 maxgabbana@gmail.com — preferred means of communication

Reside in: Belgorod

Citizenship: Russia, work permit at: Russia

Not ready to relocate, not ready for business trips

Desired position and salary

Senior Golang Engineer (Team Lead)

Specializations:

- Programmer, developer
- Development team leader

Employment: full time

Work schedule: remote working Desired travel time to work: any

Work experience — 7 years 9 months

May 2022 — till now 10 months

Qvant

Golang Team Lead

- Manage Golang development team that has been developing advertising platform
- Mentor developers and taking clue architectural decisions, transform business ideas into technical tasks

Used tools/approaches: Go, MongoDB, Nats.io, Kafka, Redis, MinIO (AWS S3 compatible storage), Jaeger, Prometheus, Grafana, Kubernetes, Gitlab CI

October 2021 — May 2022 8 months

GoStudent

gostudent.org

Senior Golang Engineer

Responsible for building micro-service oriented tutoring platform. Migrating from NodeJS to Go. Participating in fundamental architectural decisions.

Used tools/approaches: Go, CouchBase, ScyllaDB (Cassandra), ElasticSearch, Redis, Nats.io, Websockets, Protobuf

February 2021 — October 2021 9 months

Horizon Oasis

Senior Golang Engineer

Responsible for developing micro-service oriented blockchain platform. Implemented from scratch almost all micro-services related to auth, trading, order-matching, KYC/KYB, AML. Everything was hosted on AWS.

Used instruments/approaches: Go, Postgres, Redis, NATS, Docker, Websockets, REST, RPC, AWS

August 2020 — February 2021

Tabby

7 months

tabby.ai

Senior Golang Engineer

Engaged into a development process of micro-service oriented payment system Shop Now and Pay Later.

Participating in all activities.

Used tools: Golang, Postgres, Google Pub/Sub, Kubernetes, Redis, Google Cloud Platform, Gitlab CI/CD

December 2018

— August 2020
1 year 9 months

Synergist

Senior Software Engineer

One of the core people responsible for architecture and API design. Implement backend stuff using Go, MySQ, Redis, AWS. Implemented UI document prototype with ability to edit its content and save some custom editable fields using react-redux (sagas). Continued UI development along with the front-end team using react-redux and typescript. Actively participate in discussions and brainstorming.

November 2016
— December 2018
2 years 2 months

Travelmart

Senior Backend Developer

Maintained legacy functionality and created new features which allowed to make train-service faster and to sell more train tickets (get more income). I optimized SQL queries, that improved web-sites' speed. Participated actively in various ultimate system/architecture decisions. Implemented several micro-services (PHP and Golang).

June 2015 — December 2018 3 years 7 months

Suitup

Senior Full-Stack Developer

Designed backend APIs for online 3D dressing store using php/symfony. Refactored lots of old legacy backend code in php/symfony. Created dashboard functionality for moderators and application administrators. Implemented a lot of react/redux stuff. Optimized 3D model canvas drawing, which allowed to rotate it without glitches. Refactored client-side (react/redux) code by replacing all jQuery requests with axios promises and async/await ES6+ features (code looks more clean and readable). Optimized some bottle-neck sql queries that executed too slow. Integrated AWS S3 usage. Used instruments: php, symfony 1.4 (legacy), mysql, react/redux, webpack, docker, aws, git.

Education

Higher

2009

Белгородский государственный технологический университет им. В.Г. Шухова, Белгород

АПиИТ, Программное обеспечение вычислительной техники и автоматизированных систем

Key skills

Languages

Russian — Native

English — C1 — Advanced

Skills

Responsibility Proactivity Golang AWS PostgreSQL MySQL

MongoDB Redis

Further information

About me

I'm a senior level backend developer with deep experience in software development. Language polyglot. Consider it as a tool, and choose the right tool for specific issue. I have hands-on experience in doing micro-service oriented design and event-driven architecture. Always follow SOLID and DRY principles in software development.